Okay. The one other thing I want to talk about styling,
which most people don't know about when it comes to Vue 3,
is that this is great.
We have the ability to global styles,
we have scope styles, we have CSS modules.
For me, one of the things that when it comes to extending
on the functionality of the web is how we can
bring the technology together in a better way.
JavaScript is really good at interactivity,
managing state, and dynamic pieces of information.
CSS is very good at what it does, styling.
So what if you could find a way to actually merge the two together in a way
that allows for just crazy possibility?
To show you what I mean,
let's go ahead and I'm just going to save this right now.
On the app.vue, what if we wanted the ability for the user to
choose what the background color is?
Typically, the approach for that is you probably would come to
your designers and you would say,
okay, these are like the seven classes we'll support,
and so we'll try our best to just support it this way,
and so you're limited.
But there are plenty of cases where you might actually
want to give the user infinite configuration,
but the reason why we can't do that is because,
frankly, managing the CSS for that can be quite difficult.
So let's say for instance,
we have that property.
So I'm going to import a ref from view,
and I'm going to call it color preference.
It'll be a ref, it'll be an empty.
Actually, we'll just say black for now.
So what we'll do here is what you ideally want to do is you'd
like your CSS to be able to read from your JavaScript.
That would be a perfect world, wouldn't it?
Right now, what you probably have to do is some convoluted
like onload the document element,
then insert your own style tag and manipulate
the inline styles of the HTML.
There's a lot of work that goes into that.
Well, what if I said instead that what we could do is,
let's say on the app itself,
this time we're going to do a background color,
but this time I'm going to actually,
let's see, let's try to just do this.
Will color preference work?
No, nothing's happening.
Well, let's make sure it's working first.
So let's go ahead and do this.
Let's actually render out the color preference.
So color preference, where is it?
It is, oh, it's all the way down here.
Let's bump it up so it's easier to read.
Okay, great. It is showing up.
Let's make sure it actually can get
changed that it's reactive.
Let's do an import.
If you didn't know, there's a type called color on
your inputs that actually built into HTML,
and we can just V-model this to our color preference.
So let's see if this works.
Let's see, let's go this. Okay, great.
So now we have this infinite color loop.
Well, view three was like,
you know what, I think we can make this happen.
What if we just wrap this in V-bind?
So we get, shoot,
do I need to, maybe app is too far of a context?
There we go. Okay, that context was too high.
All right, it's fine. I'll just do the, let me do this.
Let me wrap this real quick.
Okay, so I'll explain why that's not working real quick.
It actually does make sense.
But for the sake of showing this, there we go.
Okay. We can see here now is you
have this infinite loop of JavaScript updating the CSS.
Now, if you're skeptical, you're like,
this looks like black magic, what's happening here?
All right, let me show you.
Let me show you.
I promise you, when we think about things,
we try to think of things in terms of extending the web.
Look at actually what's happening here.
What view does, what JavaScript does well is it says,
okay, I'm going to create a custom variable,
but we're going to use CSS variables because guess what?
That is browser technology that is actively supported,
and why would we try to reinvent the wheel?
All of JavaScript's doing is actually just
tracking this variable and just making sure to update that value.
But the rest of it is CSS.
So you get the power of CSS in
Cascades and everything in its native form,
but you also get the power of getting
reactive data that can impact those things.
So you can imagine the number of
times I've been on apps where I wanted to customize
the font size or the padding.
Those are hard to do because to create a class
for every single one of those scenarios or to
manage that at one point was nigh impossible.
But with things like vbind on your styles now,
oh, so many possibilities now exist with this.
So if you're wondering though,
why did I have a little bit of trouble with
the HTML and the app is because I think
it view once it takes over the div is unable to go outside of it.
So that's what it is.
It's just not in control,
like view is not in control of that area.
So if you're going to do this,
obviously make sure that you're within the context of your app,
otherwise the CSS won't apply.
But otherwise at this point,
you can imagine just infinite user preference configuration
that's possible with this.